You sit down now very comfortably
Now you have a desire; you put your attention to that!
Attention is very important, see?
So, the emotions are there
and then bring those emotions
and put them into your attention!
Means, they are
now you're aware of them!
Now, what you do is to watch your breathing. See now!
Try to reduce your breathing!
Reduce it
in the sense
that you have breathed out,
wait for a while,
then you breathe in
for a long time, then you breathe out.
So in one minute
your breathing will be less than normal.
Alright? Try that! Breathe in! Now with the emotions!
Keep the attention on the emotions, you see,
so that the connection is established!
hmm
Better?
Now, when you are breathing
you find that there is a space in between
which you just leave it vacant! Breathe in,
now leave it vacant!
Now breathe out,
Breathe in!
Keep it there!
And leave it,
keep outside!
Now breathe in!
Now start breathing in such a way that
you stop your breathing!
Attention should be on the heart or could be
on the emotions.
Better?
Keep the breathing inside for a while,
bring it out, then outside for a while, then again!
Then you'll find that for a while you will not breathe!
Hmm.. see? You settle down!
This exercise will give you this thoughtless awareness!
Establishment of thoughtless awareness! There is no thought!